A Guide to the John A. Barrows Photograph Collection, ca. 1930
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
John A. Barrows Photograph Collection ca. 1930
John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Library, Colonial Williamsburg Foundation
MS 1996.22
1023 items.
Photoprints, negatives, portraits, and personal papers belonging to architect and photographer John A. Barrows.
Barrows, John A.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Gift, 2003
Biographical/Historical Information
John A. Barrows was a local architect who worked on the Colonial Williamsburg reconstruction in the 1930s.
Scope and Content
The John A. Barrows Photograph Collection contains photoprints, taken mainly in Virginia and South Carolina, negatives, portraits, and personal papers and objects. The Photoprints series comprises the bulk of the collection, numbering close to 800 items. The photos, taken by architect and photographer John A. Barrows, display homes, churches, college buildings, and other structures along the eastern seaboard of the United States. Most of the photos were taken in Virginia and South Carolina, but other locations include New Jersey and Maryland. The prints were made in two sizes, 2.5x4 inches and 5x7 inches. The Negatives series has not been inventoried. John A. Barrows is the subject of the portraits found in the Portraits Series. The five images were all taken at different times. The final series, Personal Papers and Objects, includes some of Barrows' writings as well as memorabilia from trips and celebrations.
Arrangement
Arranged in series according to size and medium.
Index Terms
Persons:
Barrows, John A.
Subjects:
Photography; Architecture
Geography:
Colonial Williamsburg (Williamsburg, Va.)
Collection Contents
- Photoprints
  - 2.5 x 4” (Box 1)
    - St. Peter’s Church, New Kent Co., VA, 1-2
    - Finnie House, Williamsburg, 3
    - Magazine/ Bell’s Hospital, Williamsburg, 4
    - Powell - Hallam House, Williamsburg, 5
    - Ross/Seymore Ice House, Accomack, VA, 6
    - Rural Hill, Accomack Co., VA, 7
    - Kerr Place, Accomack Co., VA, 8-9
    - Old Merchantile Building, Accomack, VA, 10
    - St. George’s Episcopal Church, Accomack Co., VA, 11
    - Kerr Place, Accomack Co., VA, 12-14
    - Unidentified subjects in front of Armistead House, Williamsburg, 15
    - Ampthill, VA, 16-27
    - Chase-Lloyd House, 28-29
    - Ridout House, Annapolis, MD, 30
    - Acton, Annapolis, MD, 31-32
    - Hamond-Harwood, Annapolis, MD, 33-34
    - Abingdon Church, 35-36
    - Bassett Hall, 37-50
    - John Blair, Williamsburg, 51
    - Bassett Hall, 52-57
    - Bassett Hall - outbuildings, 58
    - Abingdon Church, Gloucester Co., VA, 59
    - Bassett Hall, 60
    - Barraud House, Williamsburg, 61-62
    - Barlow House, 63-68
    - Bracken House, Williamsburg, 69-72
    - Brandon, Prince George Co., 73-87
    - Blandfield, Essex Co., 88-93
    - Blandford Church, Petersburg, 94
    - Bacon’s Castle, Surry Co., 95-102
    - Archibald Blair House, 103
    - John Blair House, 104-112
    - Archibald Blair House, 113-115
    - John Blair House, 116
    - Archibald Blair House, 117
    - Bassett Hall, 118-120
    - Belle Farm, 121-122
    - Berkeley, Charles City Co., 123-124
    - Belle Farm, 125
    - Bellevue, King and Queen Co., 126
    - Bruton Parish Church, 127-132
    - Bruton Parish yard, 133-138
    - Bruton Parish Church, 139-145
    - Bruton Parish wall, 146
    - Cleve, King George County, 147
    - Coke - Garrett House, 148-149
    - Carter’s Grove, 150-173
    - Capitol, Williamsburg, 174-175
    - Courthouse, Williamsburg, 176-178
    - Capitol, Williamsburg, 179
    - Courthouse, Williamsburg, 180
    - Capitol, Williamsburg, 181
    - Courthouse, Williamsburg, 182
    - Campbell House, Lynchburg, VA, 183-187
    - Wetherburn’s Tavern, Williamsburg, 188
    - Chippokes, Surry Co., 189
    - Claremont, Surrey Co., 190-192
    - Christ Church, Lancaster Co., 193
    - 81-95 East Bay St., Charleston, SC, 194
    - City Market, Charleston, SC, 195
    - Charleston Hotel, Charleston, SC, 196
    - Theater, Charleston, SC, 197
    - 128 Church St., Charleston, SC, 198
    - City Hall/US Bank, Charleston, SC, 199
    - St. Michael’s Church, Charleston, SC, 200
    - Gibbes House, Charleston, SC, 201
    - Courthouse, Charleston, SC, 202
    - Miles Brewton House, Charleston, SC, 203
    - Gibbes Housse, Charleston, SC, 204
    - Miles Brewton House, Charleston, SC, 205
    - College of Charleston, Charleston, SC, 206
    - St. Philip’s Church, Charleston, SC, 207
    - St. Michael’s Church, Charleston, SC, 208
    - 20-30 Queen St., Charleston, SC, 209
    - Col. John Ashe House, Charleston, SC, 210
    - 22 Legare St., Charleston, SC, 211
    - Josiah Smith House, Charleston, SC, 212
    - Exchange, Charleston, SC, 213
    - Drayton, SC, 214
    - William Roper House, Charleston, SC, 215
    - Drayton Hall, SC, 216
    - Drayton, SC, 217
    - 90 East Bay, Charleston, SC, 218
    - Miles Brewton House, Charleston, SC, 219
    - Nathaniel Russell House, Charleston, SC, 220
    - St. Philip’s Church, Charleston, SC, 221
    - Unidentified, Charleston, SC, 222
    - East Bay St., Charleston, SC, 223
    - Race Hill, Charleston, SC, 224
    - Ditchley, Northumberland Co., 225-229
    - Robert Carter House, Williamsburg, 230-236
    - Tebbs House, Dumfries, VA, 237-239
    - Merchant House, Dumfries, VA, 240-241
    - Old Hotel, Dumfries, VA, 242 (Box 2)
    - Edgehill, 243-247
    - Hungar's Glebe, Northampton Co., 248
    - Eastern Shore, VA, 249-251
    - Hungar's Glebe, Northampton Co., 252
    - Eastern Shore, VA, 253
    - Courthouse Complex, Eastville, VA, 254
    - Grapeland Northampton Co., 255
    - Elkington, Northampton Co., 256
    - Vancluse, Northampton Co., 257
    - Hungar's Glebe, Northampton Co., 258-259
    - Bird's Nest Tavern, Northampton Co., 260
    - Brownsville, Northampton Co., 261-262
    - Park Hall, Eastville, VA, 263
    - Fayettville, NC, 264-265
    - Fairfield Presbyterian Church, Cumberland Co., NJ, 266-267
    - Farnham Church, Richmond Co., 268-269
    - Fauntleroy House, King William Co., 270-271
    - Firehouse, Williamsburg, 272-274
    - Four Mile Tree, Surry Co., 275-278
    - Garrett House, Williamsburg, 279
    - Galt Cottage, Williamsburg, 280-282
    - Galt House, Williamsburg, 283
    - Galt Cottage, Williamsburg, 284-287
    - Green Spring, James City Co., 288
    - Gunston Hall, Fairfax Co., 289-294
    - Powell-Hallam House, Williamsburg, 295-301
    - Harewood, Charlestown, Jefferson Co., WV, 302-311
    - Homewood, Baltimore, 312-313
    - Old Church Tower, Jamestown, 314-315
    - Church yard, Jamestown, 316
    - John Smith, Jamestown, 317
    - Pocahontas, Jamestown, 318
    - Matthew Jones House, Warwick Co., 319-322
    - Kerr House, Onancock, 323
    - Kings Mill, 324-325
    - King William Courthouse, 326
    - Margaret Hunter Shop, Williamsburg, 327-335
    - Little England, Gloucester Co., 336-344
    - Matty School, 345
    - Mattaponi Church, King and Queen Co., 346-348
    - Menokin, Richmond Co., 349-361
    - Mt. Airy, Richmond Co., 362-372
    - Mt. Vernon, Fairfax Co., 373-376
    - Marmion, King George Co., 377
    - Orrell House, Williamsburg, 378-379
    - Geddy House, Williamsburg, 380
    - Colony House, Newport, RI, 381
    - Geddy House, Williamsburg, 382
    - Neale House, Williamsburg, 383-385
    - Geddy House, Williamsburg, 386-391
    - Nelson House, Yorktown, 392-400
    - Orrell House, Williamsburg, 401
    - Gaol, Williamsburg, 402
    - John Barrows and Mary Christian, 403
    - Armistead Lot, 404
    - Barrow friends, 405
    - Greenhow-Repiton Office, Williamsburg, 406-407
    - Perry, Shaw, and Hepburn office, Williamsburg, 408
    - Powell-Hallam, Williamsburg, 409
    - Prentis Store, 410-415
    - Ludwell-Paradise House, Williamsburg, 416-419
    - Matty School, Williamsburg, 420
    - President's House, College of William and Mary, 421
    - Brafferton, College of William and Mary, 422
    - President's House, College of William and Mary, 423-432
    - Bell's Hospital, Williamsburg, 433
    - Magazine, Williamsburg, 434-436
    - Pohick Church, Fairfax Co., 437-438
    - Gaol, Williamsburg, 439-440
    - Pembroke, Virginia Beach, 441-442
    - Poplar Forest Maze, Bedford Co., 443
    - Pembroke, Virginia Beach, 444-445
    - Privy, Poplar Forest, Bedford Co., 446
    - Poplar Forest, Bedford Co., 447-449
    - Raleigh Tavern, 450-503
    - Radium, VA, 504-508
    - Peyton-Randolph House, Williamsburg, 509
    - "Rectory", 510
    - Rosewell, Gloucester Co., 511-530
    - Scrivener House, Williamsburg, 531
    - Suffolk, VA, 532-533
    - St. John House, Williamsburg, 534
    - Finnie House, Williamsburg, 535
    - Sabine Hall, Richmond Co., 536-548
    - Stratford Hall, Westmoreland Co., 549-560
    - Shirley, Plantation, Charles City Co., 561-564
    - Dependency, Shirley Plantation, Charles City Co., 565-566
    - Shirley Plantation, Charles City Co., 567
    - Side elevation, Shirley Plantation, Charles City Co., 568-569
    - Shirley Plantation, Charles City Co., 570-572
    - Side elevation, Shirley Plantation, Charles City Co., 573
    - Dovecote, Shirley Plantation, 574
    - Dependency, Shirley Plantation, 575
    - Charlton House, Williamsburg, VA, 575-580
    - Merchant's Square, Williamsburg, VA, 581-591
    - St. Augustine, FL, 592-604
    - Travis House, Williamsburg, VA, 605-612
    - Tucker House, Williamsburg, VA, 613-627
    - Thoroughgood House, Virginia Beach, VA, 628-634
    - Toddsbury, Gloucester Co., 635-636
    - Tuckahoe, Gloochland Co., 637-640
    - Tabb House, York Co., 641
    - Unknown house 1 (not Williamsburg), 642
    - Natural Bridge, Rockbridge Co., VA, 643
    - King William Courthouse, King William Co., VA, 644
    - Roscoe-Cole House, Williamsburg, VA, 645
    - Moody House, Williamsburg, 646
    - Natural Bridge, Rockbridge Co., VA, 647
    - Francis St., Block 9, Building 34, 648
    - Long Ordinary, Gloucester Co., VA, 649
    - Interior of Rosewell, Gloucester Co., VA, 650
    - Unknown house 2 (not Williamsburg), 651
    - Warwick Courthouse, Newport News, VA, 652
    - Moody House, Williamsburg, 653
    - St. John House, Williamsburg, VA, 654
    - Wales House (formerly Block 27), Williamsburg, VA, 655
    - Moody House chimney, Williamsburg, VA, 656
    - John Coke office, Williamsburg, VA, 657
    - Oystershell Road, York Co., VA, 658
    - Scrivener House, Williamsburg, VA, 659
    - Wetherburn’s Tavern, Williamsburg, VA, 660
    - Oropax? Diascund Creek?, 661
    - Detail of house in James City County, 662
    - Model of Capitol in Williamsburg, 663
    - Robert Nicholson House, Williamsburg, VA, 664
    - John Coke office, Williamsburg, VA, 665
    - Wales House (formerly Block 27), Williamsburg, VA, 666
    - Unknown house 3 (not Williamsburg), 667
    - St. John’s Church, King William Co., VA, 668
    - Wales House (formerly Block 27), Williamsburg, VA, 669
    - Unknown house 4 (not Williamsburg), 670
    - St. John’s Church, King William Co., VA, 671
    - Rear elevation, Travis House, Williamsburg, VA, 672
    - Interior, Wren Building, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 673
    - College of William and Mary, 674
    - Exterior, Wren Building, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 675
    - Unknown (probably Williamsburg), 676
    - Fairfield, Gloucester Co., 677
    - British Embassy, Washington, DC, 678
    - U.S. Capitol Building, Washington, DC, 679
    - Detail, tobacco leaf capital, U.S. Capitol, Washington, DC, 680
    - British Embassy, Washington, DC, 681-684
    - Fire, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 685-687
    - Wren Building, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 688
    - College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 689-690
    - Exterior, Wren Building, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 691
    - College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 692
    - Steps beyond present west end of Great Hall, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 693
    - College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 694-718
    - West elevation, Wren Building, College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 719
    - College of William and Mary, Williamsburg, VA, 720-727
    - Westover Plantation, Charles City Co., VA, 728-743
    - Door, Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 744
    - Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 745
    - Detail, Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 746
    - Door, Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 747
    - Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 748
    - Detail of masonry, Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 749-750
    - Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 751-753
    - Staircase, Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 754
    - Fireplace, Wilton House (now in Richmond, VA), 755
    - Wilton House, Henrico Co., 756-757
    - Wythe House, Williamsburg, VA, 758-761
    - Pine Woods/Warburton House, James City Co., VA, 762-767
    - Woodstock, Matthews Co., VA, 768-775
    - Glenroy or Exchange?, Gloucester Co., VA?, 776
    - Isle of Wight Co., VA, 777
    - Windsor Castle, Isle of Wight Co., VA, 778
    - Ware Church, Gloucester Co., VA, 779
    - Architectural staff of Williamsburg restoration, 780
    - St. Peter’s Church, New Kent Co., VA, 781
    - Merchant House, Dumfries, VA, 782
    - Hungar’s Glebe, Northampton Co., VA, 783
    - Geddy House, Williamsburg, VA, 784
    - Margaret Hunter Shop, Williamsburg, VA, 785-786
    - Lightfoot House, Yorktown, VA, 787
    - Customs House, Yorktown, VA, 788
    - Shields House, Yorktown, VA, 789
    - John A. Barrows in roadster called “Lucy”, 790
    - Diggs House, Main St., Yorktown, VA, 791
    - Thomas Waterman, 792
    - Shields House, Yorktown, VA, 793
    - Colony House, Newport, RI, 794
    - View from Nelson House toward river, Yorktown, 1914, 795
  - 5 x 7" (Box 3)
    - Rosewell, Gloucester Co., 1-4
    - Carter’s Grove, 5
    - Rosewell, Gloucester Co., 6-7
    - Mt. Airy, Richmond Co., 8
    - Abingdon Church, Gloucester Co., 9
    - Sabine Hall, Richmond Co., 10
    - William and Mary Christmas postcard, 11-12
    - Barrows Monument, Bruton Parish Church, Williamsburg, VA, 13
    - Carter’s Grove, 14-15
    - Bruton Parish Church, Williamsburg, VA, 16
    - John A. Barrows, 1929, 17
- Negatives
  - The negatives are not labeled and are not in any known order.
- Portraits
  - John A. Barrows
  - Ca. 1907
  - 1926
  - Undated, Underwood and Underwood Studios, Washington, DC
  - Nutin' But Serenaders band (Ray Williams, Johnny Barrows, Billy Belote, Jack O'Neil, MyronWhite, Everett Kent)
  - John A. Barr
- Personal Papers and Objects (Box 4)
  - Satirical cartoon depicting Governor's Palace, 1
  - Resume of the personal effects of Lord Botetourt in the Governor's Palace, 2
  - Description of Wren Building, 3
  - "June's Bungalow", short play by John A. Barrows, 4
  - "The Inventor of the Blue Print", 5
  - Scribner's Book Catalogue (lists Barrows' book), 6
  - Business card, John A. Barrows, 7
  - Christmas cards featuring photo by John Barrows, 8
  - Postcards, 9a
    - A. Vincent, 4 Rue des Beaux-Arts, Paris (more than 200), 9b
    - Selections from a set depicting Langres, France (8), 9c
    - Catedrale de St. Pierre a Geneve (Addressed to Mrs. A.P. Cooper, Belmar, N.J. and postmarked Geneve. No message), 9d
  - Framed photo, John A. Barrows in roadster "Lucy" (print 790), 10
  - Miniature portrait, subject unknown, 11
  - Pin, tercentenary celebration of Jamestown Landing, 1907, 12